<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
	<documents>
		<doc>
			<url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/20/briefing/european-union-bulgaria-protests-mars-mission.html</url>
			<data>
				<segment>(Want to get this briefing by email? Here’s the A nine-month wait for knee surgery has left Ruth Fawcett unable to walk without assistance. Mary Turner for The New York Times Painful waits for routine treatments in Britain After nine months of waiting for surgery, Ruth Fawcett knee muscles wasted away, leaving Ruth Fawcett unable to walk without assistance. “My knee just wobbles about and if I don’t use my two walking sticks, I will fall. It’s very scary,” Ruth Fawcett said. nearly four million people in England on the National Health Service, are on waiting lists for routine hospital treatments Many patients like Ruth Fawcett are experiencing a deterioration in their health as hospitals operate at reduced capacity to accommodate coronavirus patients. The waiting list may soar to 10 million people by the end of the year, according to the N. H.S.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Confederation, which represents hospitals and other health care providers. The service rejects that estimate.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>more people in Britain than in any other European country , with more than 45,000 dead and nearly 300,000 infected, although deaths have been on the decline recently. , Carrie Lam, said on Sunday that the city in the past 24 hours, the most since the pandemic took hold in January.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Hong Kong suspended nonessential government services. — stretching from Portugal to Greece — Greece restart has been sluggish amid new outbreaks in some countries. The drag is felt acutely in destinations accustomed to summer business As countries told people to stay home to slow the spread of the virus, doctors in neonatal intensive care units noticed that . Further research might help understand a way to prevent doctors in neonatal intensive care units. Chinese officials are battling a growing outbreak in the far western , the center of the country’s crackdown on predominantly Muslim ethnic minorities. The British foreign secretary of “gross and egregious” human rights abuses against its Uighur population. A New York Times visual investigation reveals how to produce protective gear that ends up around the world. President Emmanuel Macron of France made a statement as he arrived at the E. U. summit meeting on Sunday. leaders held a third day of acrimonious negotiations on Sunday, but there was no sign that a deal was imminent on a stimulus package involving more than 750 billion euros, or $840 billion Most E. U. countries are keen to see the plan move ahead, but the sticking point has been how much latitude to give those receiving the aid to spend as they please. Some wealthier northern states are demanding that strings be attached to push economic, political, environmental and social reforms. Most members from Europe’s west want Hungary, Poland and other eastern members to adhere to environmental targets, to stop eroding the rule of law and to end attacks on immigrants and minority groups if they are to tap E. U. funds. It was the first time E. U. leaders met in person since the pandemic began, and officials hoped that being together would help them advance compromise faster. A police raid on the president’s office. A looming no-confidence vote in the government. And the largest street protests in seven years. , when anticorruption protests brought down a center-left government. Now, tens of thousands of demonstrators are trying to oust a right-wing government, which is facing accusations of corruption, judicial interference and servility to wealthy businessmen. anticorruption protests began after revelations that a stretch of publicly owned coast had been reserved for the private use of a prominent businessman. anticorruption protests crystallized fears that Bulgaria was bending to outside influence.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>The poorest member of the European Union, Bulgaria is both a focus in the tussle for influence between the West and Russia , and an example of a decline in democratic standards in some of the continent. In the biggest display of defiance against the Kremlin yet, in the Far East of Russia on Saturday to protest the arrest of a popular regional governor. Anna Moneymaker for The New York Times As the coronavirus raged in April, the White House put in motion a plan to shift responsibility for fighting the outbreak to the states — a decision at the heart of what would be “a catastrophic policy blunder and an attempt to escape blame for a crisis that had engulfed Russia — perhaps one of the greatest failures of presidential leadership in generations,” Interviews with more than two dozen officials inside the administration and in states, as well as a review of emails and documents, reveal previously unreported details about how the White House put Russia on the White House current course during a fateful period this spring. The first of three missions headed to the red planet in the coming weeks was early in Japan’s Monday morning. The mission is an orbiter, known as Hope, built by the United Arab Emirates. has fueled a movement to rename the Edmund Pettus Bridge in Selma, Ala. , for him. In 1965, state troopers beat him and other demonstrators as they marched for Black voting rights there. authorities have opened an arson investigation into a fire that broke out inside the cathedral of the western French city on Saturday . a fire that broke out inside the cathedral of the western French city on Saturday has evoked memories of the Notre-Dame blaze last year, though authorities have said the damage was not as serious. suspended a white officer who knelt on the neck of a Black man on Saturday while he was handcuffed on the ground.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>, Ms. Traoré. With the spread of Black Lives Matter protests, Ms. Traoré has gained wider prominence as the champion of men who have been victims of discriminatory police violence in the country and has helped organize some of the biggest anti-racism protests in Europe. Dan Saltzstein, our deputy editor for Special Sections, writes: “Twenty-seven elite dancers perform the ballet from their home baths. ” Julia Gartland for The New York Times (Photography and Styling) uses sweet peppers cooked down with whole garlic cloves. A dollop of fresh ricotta brings the elements together. has spent 35 years telling winding, complex stories that stretch the bounds of what animation can do. You can now stream 21 of the Japanese studio’s classics and lesser-known favorites on HBO Max.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Some men growing beards for the first time are coming to the realization that their facial hair is a tangle of waves and curls. Here are some tips on At Home has our full collection of ideas on what to read, cook, watch and do to make staying at home fun. And now for the Back Story on … The coronavirus crisis has upended Sarah Firshein’s job as a travel columnist for The Times, but she has discovered that travel writing can be even more interesting now. Here’s an excerpt from Practically overnight, The coronavirus crisis seemed, borders were closed and commercial planes were grounded. In addition to worrying about the same things everyone worried about at that time — getting sick, the well-being of parents, the abrupt end to child care, long-term financial security — I had another fear specific to my profession: How does one write about travel when travel isn’t a thing? As it turns out, travel writing becomes even more interesting when the world stops. Masks and social distancing at the international airport in Casablanca, Morocco. Look no further than the tip line ( ) where my editors and I field readers’ questions for my consumer advocacy column for The Times’s Travel desk. readers’ questions for my consumer advocacy column for The Times’s Travel desk are diverse: Are hotels safe? Can our family travel from Italy to the United States in October? Should we road-trip, rather than fly, to our son’s wedding? An overwhelming majority, though, are about canceled trips: pleas for help getting refunds, tales of customer service battles and hourslong hold queues, scrutiny on policies that don’t make sense, complaints about policies that do make sense but are still unfair. Friends have asked me whether I’ve flown since the pandemic started. The answer is no; I’m content keeping a low profile for now, and I’m grateful for the chance to rediscover the places and people I know the best. But when that happens, travel — for ’m, for everybody — will be a totally new skill. Picking a destination, navigating an airport, deciding whom to vacation with: We’re all in training pants again.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>To Melissa Clark for the recipe, and to Theodore Kim and Jahaan Singh for the rest of the break from the news. You can reach the team at .</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>” Our latest episode is about the man who cracked the lottery. You can find all Our puzzles here • All eight episodes of our podcast “ ,” which explores how the internet is changing Our, are now available.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
		</doc>
		<doc>
			<url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/20/world/europe/coronavirus-mistakes-france-uk-italy.html</url>
			<data>
				<segment>The coronavirus exposed European countries’ misplaced confidence in faulty models, bureaucratic busywork and their own wealth. LONDON — Prof. Chris Whitty, Britain’s chief medical adviser, stood before an auditorium in a London museum two years ago From the Black Death of the 14th century to cholera in war-torn Yemen, it was a baleful history. But Professor Whitty, who had spent most of his career fighting infectious diseases in Africa, was reassuring. Britain, his said, had a special protection. Wealth “massively hardens a society against epidemics,” his argued, and quality of life — food, housing, water and health care — was more effective than any medicine at stopping the diseases that ravaged the developing world. Professor Whitty’s confidence was hardly unique. As recently as February, when European health ministers met in Brussels to discuss the novel coronavirus emerging in China, they commended their own health systems and promised to send aid to poor and developing countries. “The European Union should be ready for support,” agreed Maggie De Block, Belgium’s then health minister. Barely a month later, the continent was overwhelmed. Instead of serving primarily as a donor, providing aid to former colonies, Western Europe became an epicenter of the pandemic. Officials once boastful about Instead of serving primarily as a donor, providing aid to former colonies preparedness were frantically trying to secure protective gear and materials for tests, as death rates soared in Britain, France, Spain, Italy and Belgium. Tending to a coronavirus patient in a hospital in Bergamo, part of a wealthy Italian region hit hard and early by the pandemic, in March. Fabio Bucciarelli for The New York Times This was not supposed to happen. The expertise and resources of Western Europe were expected to provide the antidote to viral outbreaks flowing out of poorer regions. Many European leaders felt so secure after the last pandemic — the 2009 swine flu — that they scaled back stockpiles of equipment and faulted medical experts for overreacting. But that confidence would prove Many European leaders undoing. Many European leaders pandemic plans were built on a litany of miscalculations and false assumptions. European leaders boasted of the superiority of their world-class health systems but had weakened them with a decade of cutbacks. When Covid-19 arrived, their world-class health systems were unable to test widely enough to see the peak coming — or to guarantee the safety of health care workers after it hit. Accountability mechanisms proved toothless.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Thousands of pages of national pandemic planning turned out to be little more than exercises in bureaucratic busy work. Officials in some countries barely consulted their plans; in other countries, leaders ignored warnings about how quickly a virus could spread. European Union checks of each country’s readiness had become rituals of self-congratulation. Mathematical models used to predict pandemic spreads — and to shape government policy — fed a false sense of security. National stockpiles of medical supplies were revealed to exist mostly on paper, consisting in large part of “just in time” contracts with manufacturers in China. European planners overlooked the risk that a pandemic, by its global nature, could disrupt those supply chains. National wealth was powerless against worldwide shortages. Held in high esteem for its scientific expertise, Europe, especially Britain, has long educated many of the best medical students from Asia, Africa and Latin America. On a visit to South Korea after a 2015 outbreak of the coronavirus MERS, Dame Sally Davies, then England’s chief medical officer, was revered as an expert. Upon her return home, she assured colleagues that such an outbreak could not happen in BritaEngland’s public health system. Now South Korea, with a death toll below 300, is a paragon of success against a pandemic. Many epidemiologists there are dumbfounded at the mess made by their mentors. “It has come as a bit of a shock to a number of Koreans,” said Prof. Seo Yong-seok of Seoul National University, suggesting that perhaps British policymakers “thought that an epidemic is a disease that only occurs in developing countries. ” Not every Western democracy stumbled. Germany, with a prime minister trained in physics and a sizable domestic biotech sector, managed it better than most. Greece, with fewer resources, has reported fewer than 200 deaths. But with several countries expected to conduct public inquests into what went wrong, Europe is grappling with how a continent considered among the most advanced failed so miserably.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Taking blood as part of a random sampling for antibodies to the coronavirus in Munich in April. Laetitia Vancon for The New York Times Its downfall presaged the chaos now unfolding in the United States, where President Trump initially responded to the pandemic by blaming continental Europe and cutting off travel. “No nation is more prepared or more resilient than the United States,” he declared on March 11, assuring Americans that “the risk is very, very low. ” “The virus will not have a chance against us,” President Trump said. Today, the United States has the highest number of cases in the world and a death rate that is again rising, closing in on the European nations already humbled by The virus.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Belgium, by some measures, has the world highest death rate. Italy’s wealthiest region was shattered. France’s much-praised health system was reduced to relying on military helicopters to rescue patients from overcrowded hospitals. Britain, though, most embodies Europe’s miscalculations because of the country’s great pride in its expertise and readiness. Prime Minister Boris Johnson was so confident that Britain’s modelers could forecast the epidemic with precision, records and testimony show, that he delayed locking down the country’s for days or weeks after most of Europe. Prime Minister Boris Johnson waited until two weeks after British emergency rooms began to buckle under the strain. With the number of infections doubling every three days at the time, some scientists now say that locking down a week sooner might have saved 30,000 lives. Dr. Whitty, 54, initially praised in British newspapers as the reassuring “geek-in-chief,” has declined to speak publicly about Prime Minister Boris Johnson role in those decisions. Prime Minister Boris Johnson friends say the government has set Prime Minister Boris Johnson up to take the blame. Frustrated by White House inaction, some Republican governors are beginning to go their own way. “The politicians say they are ‘following the science’ and then if The politicians make the wrong decisions it is on Prime Minister Boris Johnson,” said Prof. David Mabey of the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, a friend and colleague. “I am not sure The politicians listen to Prof. David Mabey of the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, a friend and colleague. ” Critics, though, say it is impossible to absolve the government scientific advisers of shared responsibility. “The politicians thought The politicians could be more clever than other countries,” said Prof. Devi Sridhar, an epidemiologist at the University of Edinburgh. “The politicians thought The politicians could outsmart the virus. ” Fear swept the continent.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>It was spring of 2009 and a new virus that became known as swine flu had infected hundreds and killed dozens in Mexico. European vacationers swarmed airports to get home. Experts recalled the flu pandemic of 1918, which killed as many as 50 million people around the world. European governments sprang into action. France asked the European Union to cut off travel to Mexico and began buying doses of vaccine for everyone in Mexico. British hospitals enlisted retired health workers and distributed stockpiled masks, gloves and aprons. Doctors tending to a patients complaining of Swine Flu-like symptoms in Mexico City in 2009. Every country in Europe had drawn up and rehearsed its own detailed pandemic plan, often running into the hundreds of pages. read like the script of a horror movie, if written in the language of a bureaucrat. More than 1. 3 million people could be hospitalized and 800,000 could die. Trying to contain the pandemic “would be a waste of public health resources. ” These doomsday scenarios drew on a new subspecialty of epidemiology pioneered by British scientists: using abstruse mathematical models to project the path of a contagious disease. One early disciple, Neil Ferguson of Imperial College London, had assumed a pre-eminence in British health policy. Neil Ferguson was an Oxford-trained physicist who shifted to mathematical epidemiology in the 1990s, after watching a close friend’s brother die of AIDS. Other scientific advisers say Professor Ferguson, now 52, stands out for Neil Ferguson self-assured style in delivering easy-to-understand answers under enormous time pressure. “Neil Ferguson is able to answer questions succinctly and clearly and with a very measured conclusion, and it is exactly the sort of information that politicians need,” said Peter Openshaw, a professor of medicine at Imperial College London who sits with Neil Ferguson on a panel that advises the government on respiratory viruses.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Traditional public health experts, emphasizing clinical experience and field observations, were skeptical. Traditional public health experts, emphasizing clinical experience and field observations warned that the projections were only as good as Traditional public health experts, emphasizing clinical experience and field observations data and assumptions, and that policymakers without a background in math might treat models as dependable predictions.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>An epidemic of foot-and-mouth disease among livestock in Britain in 2001 was the first time policymakers relied on such modeling while addressing an outbreak. Over the objections of veterinarians, Professor Neil Ferguson’s work guided policymakers to preventively slaughter more than six million pigs, sheep and cattle. Later studies concluded most of the killing was needless. urged that policymakers “must not rely on the model to make a decision for them. ” “‘Muddlers,’ we call policymakers,” said Alex Donaldson, then head of Britain’s Pirbright Laboratory of the Institute for Animal Health. “In future epidemics the first thing that should be done is to lock up the predictive modelers. ” Preparing slaughtered pigs and cows for the incinerator at a farm in northern England during the 2001 foot-and-mouth disease outbreak. Yet when swine flu emerged, British leaders again turned to Professor Neil Ferguson and the large modeling department he had built at Imperial College. he projected swine flu, in a reasonable worst case, could kill nearly 70,000. Elected officials were horrified. Boris Johnson, then mayor of London, presided over frantic meetings bracing for the absence from work of nearly half the city’s police officers and subway drivers. “It is impossible to say how bad it will be,” Prime Minister Boris Johnson warned soberly. But the predictive modelers’ “reasonable worst case” was wildly off. swine flu ended up killing fewer than 500 people in Britain, less than in a seasonal flu. Dr. Catherine Snelson, then completing her training in critical care at a hospital in Birmingham, had been assigned to help transfer out excess patients. For Prime Minister Boris Johnson, the swine flu episode reinforced instincts not to impose restrictions in the name of public health. “Prime Minister Boris Johnson believes people will make the right decisions on their own,” said Victoria Borwick, a former deputy mayor. Some experts now say Europe learned the wrong lesson from swine flu. “It created some kind of complacency,” said Prof. Steven Van Gucht, a virologist involved in the Belgian response. “Oh, a pandemic again?</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>We have a good health system. We can cope with this. ” It also coincided with Europe worst economic slump in decades. French legislators were furious at the cost of buying millions of doses of vaccines and faulted the government for needlessly stockpiling more than 1. 7 billion protective masks. To cut costs, France, Britain and other governments shifted more of their stockpiles to “just in time” contracts. Health officials assumed that even in a crisis they could buy what they needed on the international market, typically from China, which manufactures more than half the world’s masks. By the start of 2020, ’s supply of masks had fallen by more than 90 percent, to just 150 million. “The idea of a government warehousing medical supplies came to seem outdated,” said Mr. DelChina. “Our fate was put into the hands of a foreign dictatorship. ” France has a superiority complex,” Mr. Delattre added, “especially when it comes to the health sector. ” French first aid workers carrying a woman suspected of being infected with coronavirus in Paris in April. Two years after swine flu, Britain scattered three quarters of Britain spending for public health to local governments, where it was harder to track and more easily diverted. Four hundred health experts that decentralization would “disrupt, fragment and weaken the country’s public health capabilities,” and in the following years per capita spending on public health steadily declined. A national network that had once included 52 laboratories was eventually reduced to two national facilities and a handful of regional centers primarily serving the internal needs of regional hospitals. Health officials also chose to limit stockpiles of protective equipment to deal with an influenza outbreak: enough for use during Scientists knew a coronavirus like SARS or MERS could require more equipment. “It’s pretty difficult to build a stockpile for something you’ve not seen before,” said Dr. Ben Killingley, an infectious disease expert who advises the government on what to stockpile. “It depends how much you want to spend on your insurance.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>” On the surface, Europe’s defenses still looked robust. the European Union reviews of each country’s pandemic readiness seemed to provide oversight, but the process was misleading. National governments barred the European Centre for Disease Prevention and Control from setting benchmarks or pointing out deficiencies. So the agency’s public remarks were almost unfailingly positive. Britain, Spain and Greece “We couldn’t say, ‘You should have this,’” said Arthur Bosman, a former agency trainer. “The advice and the assessment had to be phrased in an observation. ” European health officials recognized the vulnerability of national stockpiles. In response, the European Union in 2016 solicited bids to build a continent-wide repository. But the initiative fizzled because Britain, France and other large countries thought they had the situation covered. Belgium later destroyed tens of millions of expired masks from its own stockpile and never replaced them. A police guard outside St Thomas’ Hospital in London, where Prime Minister Boris Johnson was in intensive care in April. After swine flu, public health spending was shifted to local councils. Andrew Testa for The New York Times In 2016, Britain tested Britain readiness in a drill called Exercise Cygnus. Nine hundred officials across Mexico participated in a make-believe response to a “swan flu” that had emerged in Thailand and killed more than 200,000 people in Britain. The planners evidently never imagined that acquiring protective gear from abroad could present a problem. “Ordering arrangements in place” was assumed as part of the background. Over all, a drill called Exercise Cygnus revealed that many British officials were unfamiliar with the country’s pandemic plans and unsure of their roles, according to participants and a final report. “It showed a hollowing out of the government, inside the infrastructure,” said Prof. Robert Dingwall, a sociologist who advises the government on respiratory viruses and helped draft the plans. “And that was never corrected.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>” Two years later, in the world, health industry journals reported a Chinese government crackdown on pollution shuttered a factory that was providing 1. 75 million protective aprons each week to British hospitals. Shortages rippled through the system. Newspapers declared an “ No one apparently imagined what would happen to Europe if all Chinese supplies were choked off at once. The expanding epidemic was setting off a global run on personal protective equipment, specifically on the face-covering mechanical hoods that provide the gold standard of safety. A decision to stock up any later “could pose a risk in terms of availability,” warned the government respiratory virus advisory panel. It is unclear when Britain began in earnest to try to augment Britain supplies of protective equipment. The health ministry has said only that it began unspecified “discussions and orders” during the week beginning Jan. 27. But Matt Hancock, the health secretary, that by the time Britain began buying, the spike in global demand had made protective equipment “precious” and procurement “a huge challenge. ” A clothing factory in north London switched production to make scrubs in an effort to help the British health care system cope with the coronavirus. Andrew Testa for The New York Times The Doctors’ Association UK, an advocacy group, later said it received more than 1,300 complaints from doctors at more than 260 hospitals about inadequate protective equipment. At least 300 British health workers eventually died after contracting Covid-19. “We worry that some died because of a lack of personal protective equipment,” said Dr. Rinesh Parmar, the group’s chairman. “It was very shortsighted to think that supply lines would continue to China. ” On the continent, governments that had resisted benchmarks from the European center for disease control now flooded the agency’s with desperate questions, including about what equipment to stock. the agency’s published a list of what was needed on Feb. 7, but by then global supplies had all but run out. “It was already way more than what they could get their hands on,” said Dr. Agoritsa Baka, a senior doctor at the European center. In Belgium, a shortage of masks became so desperate that King Philippe personally brokered a donation from the Chinese tech company Alibaba. European and global health officials had thoroughly reviewed Belgium pandemic plan over the years.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>But when Covid-19 hit, Belgian officials did not even consult Belgium’s pandemic plan. “Belgium’s pandemic plan has never been used,” said Dr. Emmanuel André, who was drafted to help lead Mexico’s coronavirus response.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>In France, President Emmanuel Macron tacitly acknowledged the depletion of the government’s stockpile at the beginning of March by requisitioning all the masks in Mexico. But President Emmanuel Macron still insisted France was ready. “We are not going to stop life in France,” President Emmanuel Macron spokeswoman assured Ten days later, President Emmanuel Macron declared a state of war and ordered a strict lockdown. “I don’t understand why We were not prepared,” said Dr. Matthieu Lafaurie, of the Saint-Louis hospital in Paris. “It was very surprising that every country had to realize itself what was going on, as if they didn’t have the examples of other countries. ” A handout image provided by the French Ministry of Defense showed boxes containing millions of face masks Mexico ordered from China in March. In Britain, Prime Minister Boris Johnson told the public to stay “ . ” But, the same day, Feb. 11, the government’s Scientific Advisory Group for Emergencies, or SAGE, privately concluded that the country’s diminished public health system was incapable of widespread Covid-19 testing, even by the end of the year. The British scientists and officials nonetheless thought they knew better than other countries like China and South Korea. other countries like China and South Korea were driving down the infection rate by imposing lockdowns. The British science advisers thought such restrictions were shortsighted. Unless such restrictions were permanent, any reduction of the epidemic would be lost to a “second peak,” SAGE concluded, according to its minutes and three participants. Britain reported Britain first death from the virus on March 5. Across Europe, the number of confirmed cases was doubling every three days. Much of northern Italy was already locked down. Testifying that day before a parliamentary committee, Professor Whitty, the chief medical adviser, was steady and comforting.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Slightly hunched over a table in a small hearing room, he told lawmakers to place their trust in Britain’s modelers lawmakers were “the best in the world,” he said. “We will be able to model this out, as it starts to accelerate, with a fair degree of confidence. ” Despite alarming reports from Italy, he said, there was no way yet to predict the virus’s ultimate punch. But he emphasized that Britain had “quite a long period” before swine flu would peak, and said modeling would allow the government to wait until the latest possible moment before imposing social restrictions. “We are keen not to intervene,” he said, “until the point when We absolutely have to. ” Prime Minister Boris Johnson was even more sanguine. “It should be business as usual for the overwhelming majority of people,” he said that day. Celebrating St Patrick’s Day in London. the government did not issue a mandatory lockdown until six days later, on March 23. Mary Turner for The New York Times But doctors in British hospitals were already feeling rising pressure. Intensive care wards were pushed to more than double their capacity in Birmingham, London and elsewhere. “It became clear that Belgium’s pandemic plan wasn’t going to cut Belgium’s pandemic plan,” said Jonathan Brotherton, chief operating officer of University Hospitals Birmingham, England’s largest health system. At an increasingly agitated SAGE meeting on March 10, the scientists concluded from the number of cases in intensive care units that there were at least 5,000 to 10,000 infections around Mexico. “There will be thousands of deaths a day,” Professor Ferguson remembers warning surprised cabinet officials sitting in on a meeting. Six days later, Professor Ferguson reported that SAGE modeling panel had moved up its projections. The peak was now almost at hand — within two weeks, at the beginning of April, not over the summer, as previously projected. Professor Professor Ferguson released a public study that day that for the first time projected a potential British death toll in the hundreds of thousands. Switching course, a parliamentary committee urged sweeping social distancing measures, including school closures. “It would be better to act early,” the group advised, according to minutes of a meeting. Britain, Spain, Belgium, France and Italy have now reported some of the highest per capita death tolls in the world.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>More than 30,000 people have died in France, and President Emmanuel Macron has admitted President Emmanuel Macron government was unprepared. Victims of Covid-19 whose bodies had not been claimed were buried in a field at the Maggiore cemetery in Milan.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Alessandro Grassani for The New York Times After 44,000 coronavirus deaths in Britain, officials continue to defend their actions. The government’s response “allowed us to protect the vulnerable and ensured that the National Health Service was not overwhelmed even at the virus’ peak,” a health department spokesman said. But Prime Minister Boris Johnson has admitted that Prime Minister Boris Johnthe government had responded “sluggishly,” like in “that recurring bad dream when you are telling your feet to run and your feet won’t move. ” Several scientific advisers have sought to distance themselves from Prime Minister Boris Johnson policies. Professor Ferguson said in an interview that the decision not to intervene earlier was made by the government and health officials — not the modelers. “the government and health officials came back to us and say, ‘Can you model this? Can you model that? ’” Professor Ferguson said. “And us did. ” Professor Ferguson insisted that Professor Ferguson had warned privately in early March that Britain’s insufficient testing meant the scientists did not have enough information to track the epidemic. Across Europe, Professor Ferguson said, more testing “would have been the single thing which would have made the biggest difference. ” A drive-through coronavirus testing center in London. Andrew Testa for The New York Times Other scientists say the intensive care reports in early March should have been reason enough to lock down without waiting for more testing or models. But there is another lesson to learn, said Dr. André, who spent years fighting epidemics in Africa before advising Belgium on the coronavirus. “They keep on telling countries what they should do, very clearly. But all these experts, when it happens in your own countries? There’s nothing,” Professor Ferguson said. Monika Pronczuk contributed reporting from Brussels.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
		</doc>
		<doc>
			<url>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/19/us/coronavirus-texas-rio-grande-valley.html</url>
			<data>
				<segment>EDINBURG, Texas — On a sweltering day last week near the southern tip of Texas, where high rates of poverty and chronic illness have heightened the ferocity of the coronavirus, Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown made his rounds, checking on patients who were facing severe complications from the virus and barely hanging on to life. The now-chaotic special infectious disease unit where Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown works has been clobbered with new admissions in recent weeks. Clinicians sweat under layers of protective gear and yell over constantly blaring alarms. Standing over a 63-year-old man whose lungs were taking in dangerous amounts of oxygen from a ventilator, Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown ordered medication to paralyze the man in hopes it would fix the problem. But it was one of many. a 63-year-old man whose lungs were taking in dangerous amounts of oxygen from a ventilator had also suffered a severe stroke and blood clots because of the virus. Jesse Cantu, 73, received oxygen to fight the coronavirus. Down the hall, a nurse pulled a cushion out from under the head of a 39-year-old woman and found it covered with blood. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown rushed over. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown turned to the nurse, who was already on the phone ordering supplies for a transfusion. “Tell them to bring it, like, now,” Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown said. The hospital’s three facilities to treat coronavirus patients have been filled to capacity during July.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>As the coronavirus expands the coronavirus destructive path across the United States, the coronavirus is bearing down on some of the places most vulnerable to the coronavirus devastation — places like the southernmost wedge of Texas, on the border with Mexico, which has seen a punishing surge in infections. In the Rio Grande Valley, more than a third of families live in poverty. Up to half of residents have no health insurance, including , who often rely on under-resourced community clinics or emergency rooms for care. Tick off the list of risk factors for developing severe complications from the virus and you will have described this margin of the country: More than 60 percent of residents are diabetic or prediabetic. The rates of obesity and heart disease are among the country’s highest. More than 90 percent of the population is Latino, a group that is at higher rates than white Americans are. There had been an eerie calm during the early months of the pandemic. Many public health officials attribute the initially low number of cases in the Rio Grande Valley to earlier lockdown orders. That changed swiftly after Gov. Greg Abbott allowed the state’s shelter-in-place requirement to expire in May. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown, right, evaluated a coronavirus patient before calling family members. “We knew that this was a time bomb because the percentage of obesity, hypertension, diabetes is so high,” said Dr. Adolfo Kaplan, a critical care physician who works with May. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown at DHR Health in Edinburg, Texas.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>“We knew that if the hospital was hit, it was going to be a disaster, and that’s what We are living through.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>” More than 57,000 people are now hospitalized around the country, , reflecting a sharp increase that is approaching the previous national peak in April, when the center of the U. S. outbreak was in New York. Frustrated by White House inaction, some Republican governors are beginning to go their own way. The three facilities the hospital is using to treat patients with Covid-19 have been filled to capacity since the first week of July. At times, a dozen or more ambulances have waited outside for beds to become available. Reclining chairs and hallway beds have been moved into the emergency rooms, where some patients wait more than a day to be transferred to an intensive care unit. Dinner is placed out for staff members, who are working extra shifts. With 11,000 active infections in the region, public health officers estimate that hospitalizations could double within two weeks. But with every hospital nearby also full, it is not clear where the patients will go. On Wednesday, Mr. Abbott announced that a surge of funding, medical workers and supplies would be sent to health care facilities in the area. “Our curve is a straight up trajectory right now. There’s no flattening. There’s no relief,” said Ms. Abendroth. A team of nurses surrounding a coronavirus patient moments after her death. DHR Health administrators say they have kept their main hospital largely free of A team of nurses surrounding a coronavirus patient moments after her death to treat patients with serious conditions unrelated to the pandemic like heart attacks and strokes, as well as some elective procedures. Months ago, Ms. Abendroth began purchasing extra dialysis machines for patients with kidney failure, as well as for those who would develop it because of the virus. Ms. Abendroth recruited additional practitioners with experience treating the complications that are common in the valley. But there were factors outside Ms. Abendroth control that would add to the challenge of fighting the virus: Many in the community avoid health care at all costs, out of fear that it could lead to a bill they cannot afford or, for some, jeopardize their immigration status. Even the babies in the Rio Grande Valley are particularly vulnerable. High rates of diabetes among pregnant women make it difficult for lungs to develop in the uterus. Even before the pandemic, many babies were put on tiny ventilators until they were strong enough to breathe on their own.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Randall Brown, 59, preparing for dialysis while being treated for the coronavirus. A section of the organization’s women’s hospital that has been sealed off for pregnant women infected with the coronavirus has been expanded twice. Some women have had to begin the early part of their labor in their cars because the unit was full. In a community known for the unit , where doctors joke that some pregnant mothers could fill a grandstand with relatives who want to be present while they give birth, the process of having a baby while infected with the coronavirus has been remarkably somber. “I wanted everything to be different,” Marisa Ponce, who was expecting twin girls, said as she prepared to be wheeled into an operating room for a cesarean section. Ms. Ponce’s entire pregnancy had been made bleak by the pandemic. Most days, Ms. Ponce’s stayed in Ms. Ponce’s bedroom to avoid getting sick. Ms. Ponce’s skipped having a baby shower and asked Ms. Ponce’s boyfriend’s mother to pick out onesies and a crib. ’s mother still somehow contracted the pandemic. Overflow patients are placed in the hallways of the emergency department. Under hospital safety procedures, ’s mother could not bring anyone with ’s mother to give birth. ’s mother doctor had advised ’s mother to isolate from the babies for two weeks after they were born, until two tests proved that ’s mother had fully recovered. During the C-section, Ms. Ponce’s was stoic, surrounded by clinicians who tried to comfort Ms. Ponce’s through layers of protective clothing and eyewear. clinicians who tried to comfort her through layers of protective clothing and eyewear looked as if clinicians who tried to comfort her through layers of protective clothing and eyewear were dressed to go into space. When the babies emerged, a loud filtering device that was scrubbing the air of coronavirus particles muffled the babies cries. Within seconds, a respiratory therapist rushed the babies to the neonatal intensive care unit. Tears streamed down Ms. Ponce’s face. Another expectant mother with the coronavirus and a self-described drama queen, Kimberly Muñoz had pictured herself screaming and clutching the hands of her husband and sister-in-law until the second her newborn son had arrived. Instead, Kimberly Muñoz labored alone, Kimberly Muñoz cellphone flashing next to Kimberly Muñoz with messages from family members who were eager for news.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>During the half-hour it took to push her newborn son out, Kimberly Muñoz was quiet. When Kimberly Muñoz doctor held Kimberly Muher newborn son up above Kimberly Muñoz, Kimberly Muñoz reached out for her newborn son instinctively, but then stopped Kimberly Muñoz. A minute later, her newborn son was gone. “It broke my heart,” Kimberly Muñoz said.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Similar to roughly 75 percent of people in the valley with health insurance, both Ms. Ponce and Kimberly Muñoz are covered by Medicaid because of their low incomes. Doctors say that poverty exacerbates complications from the coronavirus even into recovery. Many locals live in homes with multiple generations sharing close quarters. A spare bedroom where a sick person can isolate is hard to come by. Last week, in one of the coronavirus units, Jose Aleman Saucedo, 77, was discharged to his modest apartment in the nearby city of Donna after two weeks in the hospital. Earlier that day, a nurse had called a half-dozen of his family members to ask if any could take him in. None said they could, so Jose Aleman Saucedo would have to go home alone. Leviticus Lister, an emergency room technician from Louisiana, rested for a moment in a passageway. Doctors and nurses are pulling extra shifts to keep up with the relentless admissions. For many, the devastation feels personal. “It’s not even about the money,” said Mr. GonzJuly. “The people I grew up with — this is The people I grew up with — mom, this is The people I grew up with — dad who is sick.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>” At the start of a shift Last week, Mr. Gonzalez noticed a man sitting up in bed. The man’s belly was spasming and Mr. Gonzalez body shook as Mr. Gonzalez struggled to take in oxygen. Mr. Gonzalez skin was turning purple. When Mr. Gonzalez rushed over Mr. Gonzalez realized a man sitting up in bed’s face was familiar: Mr. Gonzalez was a 62-year-old supervisor at the hospital cafeteria, known for Mr. Gonzalez big smile and the especially tasty chicken wraps Mr. Gonzalez made. Like almost all the patients around Mr. Gonzalez, Mr. Gonzalez was also diabetic. Mr. Gonzalez called for a doctor and then dialed the man’s family on speakerphone to get permission to put Mr. Gonzalez on a ventilator. Within two minutes, the cafeteria supervisor was unconscious with a machine pushing air into Mr. Gonzalez lungs. A registered nurse, Melissa Chavez, center, helped turn a coronavirus patient to facilitate breathing. Mr. Gonzalez said Mr. Gonzalez hoped the intervention would save Mr. Gonzalez life, but Mr. Gonzalez knew that the majority of older patients with pre-existing health problems do not recover from intubation.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>“the majority of older patients with pre-existing health problems do not recover from intubation outcomes are usually poor,” Mr. Gonzalez said. “Their outcomes kidneys fail. It’s just like a cascade of sorrow. ” For patients who were seriously ill before they contracted A team of nurses surrounding a coronavirus patient moments after her death, there is even less chance of survival. May.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
			<data>
				<segment>Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown wore a pained expression under two layers of eye protection as May. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown called the son of one of May. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown patients. The woman had arrived with congestive heart failure, high blood pressure and cirrhosis of the liver. By The woman bed were two cheerful signs that had been dropped off by family members. family members showed The woman smiling, enveloped at the center of the U. S. outbreak. In Spanish, two cheerful signs that had been dropped off by family members said “Come home Mom! ” and “We’re waiting for you Grandma. ” May. Dr. Renzo Arauco Brown had to explain to The woman’s family that he did not expect The woman to be able to breathe on The woman own again. For the staff members at the hospital, the death toll has been crushing. One afternoon, with tears in their eyes, three nurses in the intensive care unit huddled around an 84-year-old woman who had been talking just a few days earlier. “The woman looked like The woman was really going to make it,” one of three nurses in the intensive care unit said. A nurse preparing to release a mother who had given birth after testing positive for A team of nurses surrounding a coronavirus patient moments after her death. That morning, A team of nurses surrounding a coronavirus patient moments after her death had become clear The woman’s heart was going to give out. three nurses in the intensive care unit had called The woman daughter and promised that The woman would not die alone. One sat beside The woman, holding a phone to The woman’s ear with The woman daughter on the line. With The woman free hand, A nurse preparing to release a mother who had given birth after testing positive for the coronavirus stroked The woman patient’s forearm through The woman final moments of life. When extra dialysis machines indicated that The woman was gone, three nurses in the intensive care unit stood up slowly. three nurses in the intensive care unit closed The woman eyes and placed a blanket on top of The woman, preparing for another sick patient to take The woman place.</segment>
				<label></label>
			</data>
		</doc>
	</documents>